Success was once defined as being able to stay at a company for a long time and move up the corporate ladder.
成功一度被定义为能在一家公司长期任职，并沿着公司的职位阶梯步步晋升。
The goal was to reach the top, accumulate wealth and retire to a life of ease.
当时的目标是登上顶层、积累财富，然后退休，过上安逸的生活。
My father is a successful senior executive.
我父亲是一位事业有成的高级主管。
In 35 years, he worked for only three companies.
35年里，他只为三家公司工作过。
When I started my career, things were already different.
我开始职业生涯时，情况就已经不同了。
If you weren’t changing companies every three or four years, you simply weren’t getting ahead in your career.
如果你不是每隔三四年就换一次公司，事业上就根本无法取得进展。
But back then, if you were a consultant or freelancer, people would wonder what was wrong with you.
但在当时，如果你是顾问或自由职业者，人们就会纳闷你出了什么问题。
They would assume you had problems getting a job.
他们会以为你找工作有困难。
Today, consulting or freelancing for five businesses at the same time is a badge of honor.
如今，同时为五家企业做顾问或从事自由职业，是一种荣誉的象征。
It shows how valuable an individual is.
这表明了一个人的价值有多大。
Many companies now look to these “ultimate professionals” to solve problems their full-time teams can’t.
现在，许多公司指望这些“顶级专业人士”来解决自家全职团队解决不了的问题。
Or they save money by hiring “top-tier experts” only for particular projects.
或者，它们只为特定项目聘用“顶尖专家”，以此节省开支。
Working at home or in cafes, starting businesses of their own, and even launching business ventures that eventually may fail all indicate “initiative,” “creativity,” and “adaptability,” which are desirable qualities in today’s workplace.
在家或在咖啡馆工作、自己创办企业，甚至开创最终可能失败的商业项目，都显示出“主动性”“创造力”和“适应能力”，而这些都是当今职场上受青睐的品质。
Most important, there is a growing recognition that people who balance work and play, and who work at what they are passionate about, are more focused and productive, delivering greater value to their clients.
最重要的是，人们日益认识到，那些兼顾工作与娱乐、从事自己所热爱之事的人更专注、更高效，从而为客户带来更大的价值。
Who are these people?
这些都是些什么人呢？
They are artists, writers, programmers, providers of office services and career advice.
他们是艺术家、作家、程序员，以及提供办公服务和职业建议的人。
What’s needed now is a marketplace platform specifically designed to bring freelancers and clients together.
现在需要的是一个专为撮合自由职业者与客户而设计的交易平台。
Such platforms then become a place to feature the most experienced, professional, and creative talent.
这样一来，此类平台就成为展示最有经验、最专业、最具创造力的人才的场所。
This is where they conduct business, where a sense of community reinforces the culture and values of the gig economy, and where success is rewarded with good reviews that encourage more business.
他们在这里开展业务；在这里，社群意识强化着零工经济的文化和价值观；也是在这里，成功会得到好评的回报，而好评又会带来更多生意。
Slowly but surely, these platforms create a bridge between traditional enterprises and this emerging economy.
这些平台缓慢而稳步地在传统企业与这一新兴经济之间架起桥梁。
Perhaps more important, as the global economy continues to be disrupted by technology and other massive change, the gig economy will itself become an engine of economic and social transformation.
或许更重要的是，随着全球经济不断受到技术和其他巨大变化的冲击，零工经济本身将成为经济与社会变革的引擎。